I'm using a heavy duty stapler and you want to make sure you test out your stapler on a scrap piece of wood to make sure that you know where the placement of the stapler is going to be because we're on a very narrow strip here and we don't want to miss our mark when we put our stapler in.
Now with these heavy duty staplers, you want to place it and put your hand right here to give downward pressure right here because if you don't the stapler tends to want to jump up and the staple won't go in properly.
So, some of them have a little spot on top and they call it a power button and that's what they want you to do is push down and staple.
And then you have got a good staple right there nice and secure.
We're going to staple all the way down the edge and put those staples fairly close.
Now, when you're going over the whole section, you're going to need something to rest the stapler on.
Here i have just put a roll of tape, something that I can lean on.
If you don't use that, your stapler is going to go into the hole and it will shoot in the wrong direction.
So, you want to have something to prop up that stapler and we'll go about every half inch all the way down the side trying to keep those staples in a nice even row.
As a finishing touch, you might want to take a permanent marker and color over the staples so they don't stand out as much or you can touch it up with a little paint also.
Just color up those staples, it makes a big difference.
You don't notice them as much.